David Cha

Flushing, NY 11354 | 929-394-9440 | david.cha225@gmail.com <u>GitHub | Medium | LinkedIn | Personal Website</u>

Full Stack Software Engineer

Experienced Web Developer in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in Economics, Education, and Hospitality. Possess strong skills in team-building, communicating efficiently, and bringing positive energy to the team morale. Bilingual in English and Korean.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, Redux, CSS, HTML

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Shop Tracker - Frontend | Website

Web app allows users to organize their current needs on a responsive platform

- Implemented Vanilla JavaScript to fabricate a simple static website and to create a more user-friendly app
- Created the application to be more responsive with flexbox
- Constructed an auto-save feature through local storage to prevent instance data from disappearing
- Utilized custom CSS to design the layout of the website

Y.A.M.S - Frontend | Backend

Web app guide users towards the best food based on their location

- Implemented Fusion Yelp API to list the surrounding restaurants near the user
- Utilized the Mapbox API to show where the user is and to target all the restaurant's locations with React
- Constructed a user profile where they can sign-in and look at their go-to-list of restaurants as well as a log-out
- Designed it to be mobile friendly, to improve user interaction

Yap Station - Frontend | Backend

Collaborated project. Web app allows users to post status, comments, and photos

- Implemented Carrier Wave to implement photo, posts, and video posts
- Constructed a user profile where they can sign-in and look at their feeds and posts
- Designed the web app with bootstrap and CSS

EXPERIENCE

O-Toro Inc.

New York, NY

Operational Manager

9/2017 - 10/2019

- Increased Company delivery output by 10% by constructing a consistent driving routine as a solution to increase client(s) satisfaction.
- Maintained 95% clients satisfaction rate by mediating tensions between the company and clients.
- Managed the company's sale transactions to create a more organized file structure and increased the company's efficiency by 5%.

The Child Center of New York at I.S 237

New York, NY 10/2015 - 6/2016

After School Teacher/Assistant Basketball Coach

- Constructed lesson plans and taught fundamentals of the core concepts to 20 student participants.
- Built stable connections with students and co-workers which gave rise to 25% in positive communication.
- Tutored algebra to sixth, seventh, and eighth graders and helped them complete 100% of their homeworks.

(USTA) United States Tennis Association

New York, NY

Assistant Coach

6/2014 - 9/2014

- Participated in the yearly world tournament by assisting player participants, sped up the tournament process by 5%.
- Assisted the coach by managing 40% of the class with exercise and drills which involved every student in the class.
- Focused on solidifying students features which helped 8 students to progress up to the next class.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Dumbo, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 12/2019 - 4/2020

Queens CollegeFlushing, NYBachelors in Economics5/2018